# Beth Olmo

www.coderfoundry.com/betholmo

## FRAMEWORKS & PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript/ES6 JQuery Bootstrap .NET C# MVC

ASP.NET SOL & Bash

LINQ Xamarin

WebAPI

Wordpress WooCommerce

# CODER

1231 Shields Road, Suite 5 Kernersville, NC 27284 (336) 231-8632

partnerships@coderfoundry.com

This resume contains information furnished by the candidate and has not been independently verified by Coder Foundry, LLC.

This information is privileged, confidential, and to be used solely by the individual and entity to which it has been submitted.

## **EDUCATION**

**University of Maryland University College, M.S., Management** *Adelphi, MD* · 2012

Florida State University , B.S., Communication

Tallahassee, FL · 2006

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Coder Foundry, Web Software Engineer**

Kernersville, NC · July 2020 – September 2020

- Created three primary projects, including:
  - 1. A portfolio site using C#, MVC, HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSTRAP, JS & jQuery.
  - 2. A Financial Portal implemented in three phases. Phase 1: an MVC Web Application, Phase 2: a Web Service that utilizes Swagger and Swashbuckle for integrated testing, Phase 3: A cross platform Xamarin Mobile Application.
  - 3. Fully designed and developed a multi-functional issue tracker web application, implementing enhanced roles & security, which also used a Code First Relational database designed and modeled in SQL Server. Technologies used include: .Net Framework v. 4.6.1, MVC5, C#, LINQ, SQL, Entity Framework, jQuery DataTables.

## **Olmo Weinman Consulting, Web Developer / SEO / Cofounder** *Remote · 2015 – Present*

- WordPress developer & webmaster for Olmo Weinman, a professional education & web services firm providing project management certification training, business consultation, WordPress development, and webmaster services.
- Built, launched, and managed various websites, advised clients on SEO and site security best practices.
- Built custom database app on AWS for client in human resources & government contracting.

## WISE Advise + Assist, Senior WordPress Developer

Remote · 2017

- Built, redesigned, analyzed, and optimized WordPress websites for agency clients in a variety of industries and nonprofits.
- Implemented integrations for eCommerce, podcasting, memberships, appointment scheduling, whatever clients needed to promote their message and move their organizations forward.



## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

#### **Triangle Direct Media, SEO Content Manager**

Merritt Island, FL - 2014 - 2015

- Performed competitive keyword analysis using Google tools and SEMRush.
- Evaluated client website content using Google guidelines and SEOTool application.
- Collaborated with SEO Analysts on content update strategies.
- Conferred with clients to determine voice and style.
- Guided copywriters in producing content for SEO benefit and client KPI's.

## **TAG Business Strategies, Marketing Account Manager**

Windermere, FL · 2014

- Managed multiple client accounts, from on-boarding to maintenance & monitoring.
- Consulted with clients on services, target markets, etc.
- Performed SERP ranking research, website SEO analysis, and content & local listings audits.
- · Created client social media accounts.
- · Optimized client website meta data & on-page content.

#### **Eyevertise, Client Marketing Manager**

Remote · 2013 - 2014

- Managed social media marketing operations for 100+ agency clients.
- Developed, produced, and managed multiple social media profiles for each client.
- Educated and advised clients on purpose, scope, and potential usefulness of various social media platforms & directory publishers; produced & distributed tutorials for this purpose.

